<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Friendsr</string>

    <string-array name="bios">
        <item>"Arya is the third child and younger daughter of Eddard and Catelyn Stark, and is nine years old at the beginning of the book series. She has four siblings: an older brother, Robb, two younger brothers Bran and Rickon, and an older sister, Sansa. She also grows very close to her bastard half-brother Jon Snow, who resembles her in looks and is also regarded socially as an outcast."</item>
        <item>"Cersei was born the only daughter and first child of Tywin Lannister and his wife Joanna, with her twin brother Jaime born soon after. Cersei and Jaime looked so similar as children that Cersei occasionally wore Jaime’s clothes and was mistaken for him.[1] They even went as far as to experiment sexually at an early age but were discovered by a servant who informed their mother. She decided to separate them using a guard and keep this a secret from their father, threatening them that she would inform him if they ever repeated it.[2] Soon after, her mother died giving birth to their dwarf brother Tyrion. Cersei blamed Tyrion for her death, and started to abuse him as a baby"</item>
        <item>"Daenerys Targaryen is the daughter of King Aerys II Targaryen (also referred to as "The Mad King") and his sister-wife Queen Rhaella, and is one of the last survivors of House Targaryen.[6][7] She serves as the third-person narrator of thirty-one chapters throughout A Game of Thrones, A Clash of Kings, A Storm of Swords, and A Dance with Dragons. She is the only monarch or claimant to a throne given point of view chapters in the novels.[8] Thirteen years before the events of the series (sixteen in the television series), after her father and eldest brother Rhaegar were killed during Robert's Rebellion, Daenerys was born in the midst of a great storm, earning her the nickname "Stormborn". Rhaella died in childbirth and Daenerys was whisked away to Braavos with her older brother Viserys by the Master of Arms of the Red Keep, Ser Willem Darry. Darry died when Daenerys was five and she and Viserys spent the following years wandering the Free Cities.[6] By the beginning of A Game of Thrones, Daenerys has been a guest of Illyrio Mopatis in Pentos for half a year. "</item>
        <item>"Jaime was born shortly after the birth of his twin sister Cersei. The two were inseparable as children, and at an early age began an incestuous affair that continued into adulthood and even after Cersei's marriage to Robert Baratheon. At the age of fifteen he participated in the battle against the Kingswood Brotherhood, squiring for Lord Sumner Crakehall, and was subsequently knighted by Ser Arthur Dayne. While returning to Casterly Rock, he visited Cersei at King's Landing, who persuaded him to join the Kingsguard in order to be close to her. Jaime was accepted into the Kingsguard, but Tywin resigned as Hand of the King, taking Cersei with him back to Casterly Rock. Jaime quickly realises that Aerys named him to the Kingsguard solely to strip Tywin of his heir. Jaime becomes further disillusioned after witnessing Aerys burn Rickard and Brandon Stark alive and overhearing him raping his sister-wife Rhaella. When Tywin begins sacking King's Landing at the climax of Robert's Rebellion, Jaime realises that Aerys intends to burn King's Landing with wildfire and kills him, almost immediately being discovered by Tywin's men. Robert Baratheon later pardons Jaime for breaking his vows and names him to his own Kingsguard. Although Jaime considers his assassination of Aerys as his greatest act, his motives for killing him remain unknown to the rest of the realm and he is given the insulting moniker "Kingslayer". Several years later, he and Tyrion rescue a young woman, Tysha, from outlaws, and Tyrion secretly marries her. When Tywin finds out he orders Jaime to tell Tyrion that he staged the incident in order for Tyrion to lose his virginity. Though it is unknown if Jaime was aware that Tywin subsequently forced Tyrion to watch Tysha be gang-raped by his guards, Jaime carries a great amount of guilt for his unkindness to Tyrion in his later years."</item>
        <item>"In A Game of Thrones, Jon Snow is introduced as the 14-year-old illegitimate son of Eddard "Ned" Stark, Lord of Winterfell, and half-brother to Robb, Sansa, Arya, Bran and Rickon. Jon is described as having strong Stark features with a lean build, long face, dark brown hair and grey eyes.[5] Jon has the surname "Snow" (customarily used for illegitimate children in the North) and is resented by Ned's wife Catelyn, who views him as a constant reminder of Ned's infidelity.[4] Jon is the same age as Robb and enjoys a warm relationship with his siblings, particularly the tomboy Arya (who resembles Jon and like him does not feel like she fits in). Ned treats Jon as much like his other children as propriety and his honor will allow. Still, as somewhat of an outsider, Jon has learned to be independent and to fend for himself when necessary. Jon idolizes his father, but is wounded by Ned's refusal to tell him about his mother.[6] At the beginning of the story, Jon adopts the albino direwolf that he names Ghost. He later finds that at times he can "inhabit" the wolf and share its experiences."</item>
        <item>"Ser Jorah Mormont is the only child of the Night's Watch's Lord Commander Jeor Mormont, who abdicated shortly before Robert's Rebellion to join the Night's Watch and let Jorah assume the lordship of Bear Island. At some point Jorah married a lady of House Glover, who died from miscarriage after ten years of marriage. Jorah fought in Greyjoy's Rebellion, distinguishing himself by being one of the first to enter the fray during the Siege of Pyke, and was knighted by King Robert Baratheon. At the Tourney of Lannisport celebrating the Baratheon victory, Jorah fell in love with the beautiful Lynesse Hightower (aunt of Margaery Tyrell), and named her Queen of Love and Beauty after winning the tourney. Lynesse's father agreed to their marriage, and although Lynesse reciprocated his love she soon found herself ill-suited to the rough life on Bear Island, longing for the splendour and comfort of her youth in Oldtown. Jorah bankrupted himself trying to provide her with luxuries, eventually selling poachers to a Tyroshi slaver to fund her lifestyle. His liege lord, Eddard Stark, condemned him to death, but Jorah and Lynesse fled to the Free City of Lys. Jorah made his living as a sellsword, though still unable to provide for Lynesse. One year he returned from fighting Braavos on the River Rhoyne to find that Lynesse had become a concubine of a wealthy Lysene merchant. The merchant warned Jorah that he would be enslaved to settle his debts if he remained in Lys, and Jorah was forced to flee again. Afterwards he drifted between the Free Cities, offering his services to the highest bidder, and at one stage joined the Second Sons mercenary company."</item>
        <item>"Margaery is the only daughter of Alerie Hightower and Mace Tyrell, the Lord of Highgarden in the Reach. Her older brothers are the heir Willas, Garlan and Loras the Knight of Flowers, who is a member of the Kingsguard. One of the wealthiest and most powerful families in Westeros, House Tyrell is actually guided by the willful Lady Olenna, Mace's mother, who has arranged Margaery's marriages and mentors her in politics and court intrigue."</item>
        <item>"Also known as "The Red Woman", Melisandre is a shadowbinder and a priestess of R'hllor in service to Stannis Baratheon. Originally a slave from Asshai called Melony, she is chosen by the Red Temple and recruited as a red priestess, and as a result has prophetic powers that give her partial knowledge of future events. She is also referred to as a shadowbinder, being able to cast glamours and perform certain feats of dark magic. Melisandre is introduced in A Clash of Kings and serves as the third-person narrator for one chapter of A Dance with Dragons. She is described as a beautiful voluptuous foreign woman with red eyes and red hair, always dressing in red robes and wearing a red gold choker set with a large ruby, and rarely sleeps or eats. She possesses magical abilities that can cast glamour and manipulate fire and shadow, has prophetic visions by looking into fire, and takes an aggressively militant stance against the other religions of Westeros."</item>
        <item>"Sansa Stark is the second child and elder daughter of Eddard Stark and Catelyn Stark. She was born and raised in Winterfell, until leaving with her father and sister at the beginning of the series. She was raised with a younger sister Arya Stark, two younger brothers Rickon Stark and Bran Stark, as well as an older brother Robb Stark, and an older illegitimate half-brother, Jon Snow.
Raised as a lady, Sansa is traditionally feminine. Sansa's interests are music, poetry, and singing. She strives to become like the heroines of romantic tales by attempting to find a prince, knight, or gentleman to fall in love with. For a companion animal, she owned a direwolf named Lady. However, Lady was killed in place of Arya's direwolf, Nymeria, in the first installment. Lady is killed because Nymeria attacked the Crown Prince, Joffrey Baratheon and later fled."</item>
        <item>"In A Game of Thrones (1996), Tyrion is introduced as the third and youngest child of wealthy and powerful Tywin Lannister, the former Hand of the King, and Joanna Lannister, who dies giving birth to him. Tyrion's elder sister Cersei is the Queen of Westeros by virtue of her marriage to King Robert Baratheon, and Cersei's male twin Jaime is one of the Kingsguard, the royal bodyguard. Described as an ugly ("for all the world like a gargoyle"), malformed dwarf with different colored eyes, green and black, Tyrion possesses the golden blond hair of a Lannister but has a complicated relationship with the rest of them.[8][9] While he is afforded the privilege and luxuries of his family, he is treated as a "second class noble" because of his stature.[10] Tyrion's mother Joanna died giving birth to him and Tywin and Cersei loathe him because they blame him for her death. While Tywin bears no affection for Tyrion, he nevertheless feels a sense of duty to his son, raising him in the Lannister fold and extending Tyrion a share of the family wealth. In contrast to Tywin and Cersei, Jaime has great affection for Tyrion and treats him with kindness, respect, friendship and love."</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
